Hi, everybody. Um I wanna thank TLT for the invitation to present.
Um And for all of you to who,
who shared your time to come here so that I can tell you about my course.
All right, we'll start.
So just two weeks ago
um at the Goldman Sachs talks, Ceo Peter Fagi
from the
Ann
Anna Freud
um Center
commented that young people are becoming less and less
happy as a result of their screen time.
Why? Because of the lack of human interaction,
I'm here to tell you that it depends on how you think about it
and how you use it.
We are tasked to create a collaborative learning community
online.
That's what the le program does that we
have a seminar style learning community education,
the College of Fine Arts, however,
um was being left out of our ability to deliver that service. Why?
Because those students have such intense face to face daily schedules that
they cannot get their requirements done with a face to face course.
So they asked us specifically to create
an online course for those particular students.
But the challenge was to create an online course that enables community.
So that is what we did.
Imagine
creating an art history course with the
ad a requirements of presenting this painting,
Vincent Van
Gogh's Starry Night
to a, a legally blind student. Well, I've had to do that
and I took that same approach that I took with that student and making sure that
he got the same learning outcomes that everyone else did in my class to this project
to give the same learning outcomes that we get in a face to face seminar
in an online environment.
And I thought about it this way and this is where Chris or my designer um
and I met had a meeting of the minds. We both have mbas
and we thought about this as the goal determines your means of delivery.
So to create the highest quality educational experience
for our online learning community of freshmen,
fine art students,
we harnessed the capabilities of canvas that are typically
um well created and made for a lecture style course.
Um And we adapted it to a seminar style by pushing beyond
the limits of canvas and bringing in new technologies to do that.
So then the next set of slides I want to show you what we did.
Um First let me tell you what the preparation took. And this took a lot of work.
I attended the TLT Faculty boot camp, which I would highly recommend to anybody.
I used the alignment grid that was created by TLT
um to create a very tightly integrated
curriculum which is absolutely essential if you're
going to innovate on top of a really solid foundation for your course.
I also thanks to um the le program,
they funded my ability to attend an
international conference on elearning and innovative pedagogy.
So I could see what cutting edge looked like.
And then Chris and I both um shared best practices. We researched a lot
and then I created prototypes that I tested
out on students and peer advisors in advance
uh developed strong collaboration with my course designer.
And then also um the video support that I was offered at TLT.
And then thanks to Corey Stokes who made this all possible and set the
bar high by giving me the challenge of Make Me a showcase course.
Um So that's what we, we worked really hard and we wrote your Fleas, Corey.
Um One of the things that we
uh incorporated were evocative visuals absolutely essential.
If you're going to capture the attention of fine art students,
they are used to aesthetics.
Um And one of the things and one of the challenges of
online education is getting a student motivated enough to turn on that computer
and get connected just to even start.
So um uh Chris will be showing you a little bit more about what that means.
If you look just here on this slide,
the black arrows are indicating what canvas provides.
I found that very limiting.
It's so structured it's so linear, it's boring and it's formal,
especially for a fine art student.
So we added in visual and I said, I don't want just something attractive.
It's got to move and it's got to move.
Not in a repetitive worrying way,
but it's got to be engaging and it has to give those students information
at a glance,
what is going to happen in the module that
they're going to study so that they already have
an end to that material and they're already engaged
just from because an image is worth 1000 words.
And then we've also added in checklist and introductory videos.
So they know what they have to do and they know why.
Secondly, the content matrix was entirely student
focused.
It's not just about content but about who those students
are as learners and how we can engage them better.
So I created an innovative um uh curriculum just specifically for them, the
they are gaining um social science, general education credit.
But I um made sure to show how the application
of each of those social sciences to the fine arts,
but using real world examples that are current so that the students would see the
relevance of what they're learning and be familiar with it um through the fine arts,
through that, through that lens,
uh the in the curriculum is integrated with very clear objectives,
progressive difficulty and complexity as you
move through the course and then latter
social interactions very important in building
communities starting with just simple introductions.
But by the time they're done,
there are engaged in very intense teamwork and community um activities.
We also created custom features just specifically for this course to try
to emulate what it's like to be in my face to face.
Course, one of the things I do with freshmen,
um they are not practiced readers yet.
I want I guide them through an article that's best practices about what
a real social science research um article looks like the components of that.
So we created an annotated version with video inserts of me inside the article
that guide them through so that they know how to read that article.
Uh In addition to our checklist also pro project charts,
so they know what they have to do,
how much they've already accomplished and where they're headed
now they can manage their time more easily,
then how to tutorials with um
view code.
Sure,
since I've been tracking it
working full time
G
and what it does is it shows a, a video clip that moves um just in a subtle motion
and what this uh it's actually kind of an old technology,
but we used it to affect here in the class because canvas actually deals with, with,
with this just fine.
And what this does is for the students.
It gives them a signpost,
it gives them an idea of what is the information
they're going to be going over in this course.
And so, and like you said,
the aesthetics were very important to the students that come in through this class.
And
uh so we've had a lot of really good feedback on this. This is kind of a neat
um uh this video is from a set of people who still make handmade globes.
Um And then you also mentioned the learning tree exercise. There is a tool called um
uh
CALC
Js.
So it's a javascript type uh calculator where we created this slider
where students could try to figure out how um their pay,
how a student would pay for college.
So you figure out your um tuition costs your hourly
wage and whatnot and tax rate and all that.
And it all comes up in here real time.
This is a, a tool that's outside of canvas, like I said,
but it embeds into canvas and you can uh the students
did this exercise as a simulation and then they
would come in and um do a reflection about
how difficult it was to try to figure out how to pay for uh pay for college.
And then uh
this is slack that we were talking about.
Once again, this is uh like you were saying, this is not an academic tool.
This is very popular in uh start ups, actually seven or $8 billion company now.
Um And uh we've been very happy with the um
a lot of people who use the the boards that automatically grade,
this doesn't automatically grade but you can, when you post into Slack,
you can get a URL for your post,
which is something that you can take back and turn into canvas.
And then
when Dr Brown was doing her grading,
she could click on that link and go straight to what the students wanted to highlight
as their
uh as the answer for their assignment.
What I thought was really cool is when we started looking through this,
the branches of conversation that just came off of all
of the things that the students were talking about.
I mean, there is a linear
to it just for order of conversation of who's talking and whatnot.
But for the idea of getting in the students into another place to, to talk,
this doesn't end up with the discussion board being,
you know, the question being
uh two plus two and then someone responds,
I really like how you added the two to the two
and got four great job.
So we felt like this worked out really well.
And it also um worked with the aesthetics again because people could post videos,
pictures and they've been doing that um based on the subjects that
you've been giving on and ones that they've been doing themselves.
So
once again, what was really rewarding on this project was that
uh Doctor Brown would come and she'd have
an idea of something she wanted to accomplish.
And we had uh really kind of no idea where we were gonna end up with a solution.
But she was really open to looking at new ideas and tools and
uh um working with things that weren't the perfect solution,
they were something that came in
and she had to work with.
And I think that was a testament to you working with
the innovative tools here and for the benefit of the students.
So
thank you very much.